ILGWU Miscellaneous Audio Cassettes 5780/134 AV
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
ILGWU Miscellaneous Audio Cassettes
1953-1984
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union
5780/134 AV
17 cubic feet
16 linear ft.
Audiovisual materials.
Audio recordings of ILGWU interviews including "Pins and Needles" cast, Dan Meyers, Lee Morrison Cooley, Clara Larsen and Rebecca Leff, Herman Rotsten and Alma Charmer Rotsten, Ida Mandell, as well as other miscellaneous interviews, conferences and meetings
7128222
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, May 28, 2013
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, April 15, 2019
Biographical / Historical
The International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union was once one of the largest labor unions in the United States founded in 1900 by local union delegates representing about 2,000 members in cities in the northeastern United States. It was one of the first U.S. Unions to have a membership consisting of mostly females, and it played a key role in the labor history of the 1920s and 1930s. The union is generally referred to as the "ILGWU" or the "ILG". The ILGWU grew in geographical scope, membership size, and political influence to become one of the most powerful forces in American organized labor by mid-century. Representing workers in the women's garment industry, the ILGWU worked to improve working and living conditions of its members through collective bargaining agreements, training programs, health care facilities, cooperative housing, educational opportunities, and other efforts. The ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union in 1995 to form the Union of Needle trades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE). UNITE merged with the Hotel Employees and Restaurant Employees Union (HERE) in 2004 to create a new union known as UNITE HERE. The two unions that formed UNITE in 1995 represented only 250,000 workers between them, down from the ILGWU's peak membership of 450,000 in 1969.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5780: ILGWU records
Clothing workers -- Labor unions -- New York (State) -- New York; Women's clothing industry -- Labor unions -- New York (State) -- New York; Industrial relations -- New York (State) -- New York
7128222
- Interviews with "Pins and Needles" cast members, 1 (Box 4)
- Interviews with "Pins and Needles" cast members, 1 (Box 5)
- Interviews with Dan Meyers, 1 (Box 6)
- Interviews with Dan Meyers, 1 (Box 7)
- Interviews with Lee Morrison Cooley, 1 (Box 8)
- Interviews with Lee Morrison Cooley, 1 (Box 9)
- Interviews with Lee Morrison Cooley, 1 (Box 10)
- Interviews with Lee Morrison Cooley, 1 (Box 11)
- Interviews with Clara Larsen and Rebecca Leff, 1 (Box 12)
- Interviews with Clara Larsen and Rebecca Leff, 1 (Box 13)
- Interviews with Clara Larsen and Rebecca Leff, 1 (Box 14)
- Interviews with Herman Rotsten and Alma Charmer Rotsten, 1 (Box 15)
- Interviews with Herman Rotsten and Alma Charmer Rotsten, 1 (Box 16)
- Interviews with Herman Rotsten and Alma Charmer Rotsten, 1 (Box 17)
- Interviews with Herman Rotsten and Alma Charmer Rotsten, 1 (Box 18)
- Interview with Ida Mandel, 1 (Box 19)
- Interview with Ida Mandel, 1 (Box 20)
- Interview with Ida Mandel, 1 (Box 21)
- Interview with Ida Mandel, 1 (Box 22)
- Gus Tyler, addressing Leadership Class in Auditorium - 10/1/1974, 1 (Box 23)
- Leon Stein Addressing Leadership Class in Aud. - 10/8/1974, 1 (Box 24)
- Evelyn DuBrow Addressing Leadership Class in Aud. - 10/15/1974, 1 (Box 25)
- David Zalinka, addressing Leadership class in aud. - 10/22/1974, 1 (Box 26)
- David Dubinsky: ;Midday I.N.NE WS: SPIX/TV: 9/17/1982, 1 (Box 27)
- David Dubinsky: Midday I.N.NE WS: SPIX/TV: 9/17/1982, 1 (Box 28)
- David Dubinsky: News: WHN Radio Sept. 17, 1982, 1 (Box 29)
- David Dubinsky: News: WHN Radio, Sept. 17, 1982, 1 (Box 30)
- David Dubinsky: WNEW/AM (NY) News: Sept. 17 1982, 1 (Box 31)
- David Dubinsky: WNEW/AM (NY) News: 9/17/1982, 1 (Box 32)
- David Dubinsky: WVNJ Radio News: Sept. 17, 1982, 1 (Box 33)
- David Dubinsky: News WABC Radio, Sept. 17, 1982, 1 (Box 34)
- David Dubinsky: News: WABC Radio, Sept. 17, 1982, 1 (Box 35)
- Wins - 9/17 - David Dubinsky, 1 (Box 36)
- Stat: WINS; Prog: NEWS; Date: 9/17/1982, 1 (Box 37)
- Stat: WOR Radio - 9/17/1982, 1 (Box 38)
- STAT: WBAI - FM - 9/17/1982, 1 (Box 39)
- Stat: WBAI-FM - 9/17/1982, 1 (Box 40)
- ITGLWF Dublin - Sol. C. Chaikin - 3/23/1976, 1 (Box 41)
- Charkin - Trade Adjustment - June 9, 1978, 1 (Box 42)
- Sol. C. Chaikin, ACTWU Convention, Los Angeles, California - 9/28/1978, 1 (Box 43)
- Swedish Broadcasting Corp. Interview Mr. Sol Chaikin, ILGWU - 10/26/1978, 1 (Box 44)
- American Federation of Labor and Congress of Industrial Organizations - 13th Constitutional Convention11/16/1979, 1 (Box 45)
- Enterprise Zones - Reagan's Mythical Job Creation, 1 (Box 46)
- Sol C. Chaikin, President, ILGWU - Labor News Conference - 4/27/1982, 1 (Box 47)
- S. Chaikin - 6/17/1982, 1 (Box 48)
- Pres. Sol C. Chaikin - Speech - 3/5/1983, 1 (Box 49)
- Opening of exhibit, 275 Seventh Ave. ILGWU Archives, 1 (Box 60)
- Chaikin - 5/24/1984, 1 (Box 50)
- ILGWU Convention - 1977 (Side 1), 1 (Box 51)
- ILGWU Convention - 1977 - (side 2), 1 (Box 52)
- ILGWU Convention - 1977 (side 3), 1 (Box 53)
- 26 ILGWU Member Interviews - 6/2/1984, 1 (Box 55)
- Bonano Breakfast, 1 (Box 54)
- 1953 ILGWU Local 91, 1 (Box 56)
- Together: an Anthem for the UAW's 50th Anniversary, 1 (Box 57)
- Interview with Abe Ruscho - 1/12/1984, 1 (Box 58)
- John Fruda's Seminar, 1 (Box 59)
- Meeting GEB - Louis Stulberg Resign, 1 (Box 61)
- Pres.. Stulberg's Report - 3/3/1975, 1 (Box 62)
- Staff Meeting - 11/13/1970, 1 (Box 63)
- Friends of Carter-Mondale Dinner - Oct. 24, 1979, 1 (Box 64)
- Stulberg, Mendelson & Dubinsky Installation - 3/27/1971, 1 (Box 65)
- Jt. Council - Unity House - 6/6/1976, 1 (Box 66)
- Tokyo - July 13, 1978 - International Communications Agency, 1 (Box 67)
- The City Club of New York - March 5, 1982, 1 (Box 68)
- Stat: WCBS Radio Pro: News - 9/17/1982, 1 (Box 69)
- Stat: WCBS Radio Pro: News: - 9/17/1982, 1 (Box 70)
- Stat: WNET-TV - Pro: Nightly Business Report - 9/17/1982, 1 (Box 71)
- Stat: WNET-TV - Pro: Nightly Business Report - 9/17/1982, 1 (Box 72)
- Israel Histadrut Exec. Council - 6/25/1978, 1 (Box 73)
- Press Conference @ Chaikin - 3/21/1979, 1 (Box 74)
- Cornell - 11/13/1978, 1 (Box 75)
- Joint Symposium on the Middle East - Tuesday - May 30, 1978, 1 (Box 76)
- Wilbur Daniels - ILG Institute - 10/21/1971, 1 (Box 77)
- Blue Collar Workers in Eastern Europe - Sol C. Chaikin - May 14, 1980, 1 (Box 78)
- WCBS - 4/24- ILGWU, 1 (Box 79)
- Chile - Mon. May 22, 1978 - Executive - Rios - Bogel - Tucopel, 1 (Box 80)
- Cloak Joint Board, Board of Directors, "Restructuring" - Nov. 11, 1971, 1 (Box 81)
- Victor Reisel show with Henoch Mendel5/17/1971: Ralph Shomer, 1 (Box 82)
- Jt. Council Merger - 7/17/1976, 1 (Box 83)
- Stat: WMCA Radio - Pro: Ralph Howard: - 4/20/1982, 1 (Box 84)
- Press Conference - Argentina - 9/1977, 1 (Box 85)
- SCC Hearing Group Meeting - 4/26/1980 - Re: FLSA, 1 (Box 86)
- WINS - Radio-News - 4/23/1983 - ILGWU Rally, 1 (Box 87)
- UN Mission - Pat Moynihan & Social Dem. - Jan. 1976, 1 (Box 88)
- Chaikin - COT - 12/11/1975, 1 (Box 89)
- Trilateral (Zimmerman) - Corporate Responsibility, 1 (Box 90)
- Destination America - Jews - 10/3/1976, 1 (Box 91)
- WEVD Abe Raskin Interviewer- 10/28/1977, 1 (Box 92)
- Howard Molisani, 1 (Box 93)
- David A. Morse - Installation - 2/12/1970, 1 (Box 94)
- Chairman Discussion, 1 (Box 95)
- Joint Executive Board Meeting - 8/1/1972 - Presentation of Charters, 1 (Box 96)
- Dr. Milton Sachs - September 1971, 1 (Box 97)
- 1st. Rep. Meeting, 1 (Box 98)
- Mendelson after Rollick - Sol Bonger, 1 (Box 99)
- ILPA - Dec. 5, 1977, 1 (Box 100)
- AFL-CIO - Dec. 1977, 1 (Box 101)
- President Truman - T. Bankmead - Vice Pres. Barkley - M. Dovelas - H.G. Douglas, 1 (Box 102)
- ILGWU 1948 - Campaign Committee - Presents "Truman, Barkley and Labor", 1 (Box 103)
- Getting to Know, 1 (Box 104)
- Organized Labor's View of the American Labor Scene, 1 (Box 105)
- Chairman Discussion, 1 (Box 106)
- SCC on Mendelsund, 1 (Box 107)
- Stulberg, 1 (Box 108)
- David Morse, President Stulberg, 1 (Box 109)
- ILGWU - Puerto Rico, 1 (Box 110)
- The War College - 2/4/1977 - Questions and Answers, 1 (Box 111)
- Nov. 19, 1977 - Histadrut Convention., 1 (Box 112)
- Histadrut - Detroit - March 1978, 1 (Box 113)
- Louis Stulberg, Jewish Labor Committee - 11/23/1970, 1 (Box 114)
- American Immigration & Citizenship Conf. Luncheon, April 9 - Plaza Hotel, NYC - 1976, 1 (Box 115)
  Scope and Contents
  See transcripts in Series X, Speeches, 5780/083, Sol Chaikin Papers
- Taiwan after Mao - Nov. 30, 1976, 1 (Box 116)
- Chile Press Conf. - Re: Pinochet - May 23, 1978, 1 (Box 117)
- Tai Lateral Conf. - June 11, 1978, 1 (Box 118)
- Europe-NATO-Turkey-Non-Democratic Threat, 1 (Box 119)
- Columbia Univ. at Arden House - June 15, 1978, 1 (Box 120)
- Questions an d Answers on Columbia Univ. at Arden House - June 15, 1978, 1 (Box 121)
- Questions continued - June 15, 1978 - Arden House, 1 (Box 122)
- Tokyo - 7/13/1978; Histadrut San Fran. - 7/15/1978, 1 (Box 123)
- Work in America - March 14, 1979, 1 (Box 124)
- Scarborough - April 23, 1979; Congress, Nat'l. Union of Tailors & Garment Workers, 1 (Box 125)
- Chaikin Speech - Amer. Ed. - Nov. 1, 1979, 1 (Box 126)
- Chaikin & Mendelsund - 1/24/1980 - opening of Archives, 1 (Box 127)
- Jan. 24, 1980 - Opening, exhibit of Archives, 1 (Box 128)
- Midtown Realty Owners Luncheon - Nov. 2, 1978, 1 (Box 129)
- Stat: WOR Radio / PRO: News - 9/17/1982, 1 (Box 130)
- David Dubinsky: WVNJ Radio - News: Sept. 17, 1982, 1 (Box 131)
- June 29, 1976 - Union Business, 1 (Box 132)
- Interview with Tarei - 5/4/1976, 1 (Box 133)
- Interview with Morris Novik, May 4, 1979, 1 (Box 134)
- Interview with Cast Member Don Meyers, 1 (Box 135)
- Interview with Cast Member - Lee Morrison Cooley, 1 (Box 136)
- Interview with Cast Member - Lee Morrison Cooley, 1 (Box 137)
- Interview with Case Member - Ida Mandel, 1 (Box 138)
- Interview with Cast Member - Joe Aleasa, 1 (Box 139)
- Interviews with Clara Larsen and Rebecca Leff, 1 (Box 140)
- Interview with Cast Members Herman Rotsten and Alma Charmat Rotsten, 1 (Box 141)
- Interview with Cast Members Herman Rotstein & Alma Charmat Rotstein, 1 (Box 142)
- Unlabeled, 1 (Box 143)
- Unlabeled, 1 (Box 144)
- Unlabeled, 1 (Box 145)
- Unlabeled, 1 (Box 146)
- Hymns, 1 (Box 147)